Li **KEVIN** Wenliang

kevinliw@deepmind.com

% www.kevinwli.net

☆ 6 Handyside St, London N1C 4UZ, UK

I am interested in finding general principles of intelligence underlying artificial and biological agents. In capability research, I work on generative models, approximate inference and density estimation, with a particular focus on time-series data and training flexible/deep models. For scientific research, I reveal failure modes and elucidate success factors of existing methodologies, raising awareness for theoreticians and practitioners. I draw inspiration from cognitive neuroscience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2022-pres. DeepMind Research Scientist, Universal Artificial Intelligence

Developing state-of-the-art models in sequence prediction and uncertainty quantification

Understanding and interpreting large-scale image and language models

2021-pres. University College London Honorary Research Fellow, Wellcome Trust Centre for Neuroimaging

EDUCATION

2015-2021 Gatsby Unit, University College London

PhD in Machine Learning and Theoretical Neuroscience

Advisors: Maneesh Sahani and Peter Dayan

Thesis: Nonparametric Enrichment in Computational and Biological Representation of Distributions

2010-2014 University of Cambridge, Trinity College

BA (Class I) and MEng (Distinction), Information Engineering. Advisor: Máté Lengyel

Scholarship: £18,510 p.a. for four years, Trinity College Senior Scholar

Ranking: top 10 for 1st, 2nd, and 4th years (3rd year at MIT) among > 300 students

Master thesis: Inference and Learning on a Nonlinear State-space Model for Spiking Data

2012-2013 Massachusetts Institute of Technology

Cambridge-MIT Exchange in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science, GPA 4.9/5.0.

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

2020-2021 Amazon Web Services, Shanghai Research Scientist Intern, with David Wipf

2020-2021 Department of Psychology, University of Cambridge Visitor to Zoe Kourtzi, visual perceptual learning

2020-2021 Institute of Neuroscience, Chinese Academy of Science Visitor of Liping Wang, sequence perception

7 / 2016 Brains, Minds and Machines Summer School, Woods Hole Participant

1-4 / 2015 Tsinghua University, Beijing Research Assistant, grasp planning, with Fuchun Sun

6-10/2014 Microsoft Research Cambridge Research Intern, computer vision, with Sebastian Nowozin

6-9 / 2013 Microsoft R&D, Shanghai Program Manager Intern, payment security

6-9 / 2011 Swiftkey (acquired by Microsoft), London Engineer Intern, natural language processing

Reviewer: JMLR, TMLR, NeurIPS (top 10%), ICML (expert), ICLR, AISTATS, Neurocomputing, Neural Computation

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

7 / 2023 Computational and Cognitive Neuroscience, Suzhou TA in Maths, Deep Learning; mentored 6 projects

7 / 2021 NeuroMatch Academy Summer School, online project mentor, course content consultant

7 / 2020 NeuroMatch Academy Summer School, online TA in theoretical neuroscience

7 / 2019 Machine Learning Summer School, London TA in machine learning

2016-2017 Gatsby Unit courses, London TA in unsupervised learning, theoretical and systems neuroscience

INVITED TALKS

3 / 2021 Beijing Normal University, Ke Zhou Lab Postdictive inference in perception

1 / 2021 Chinese Institute for Brain Research, Beijing Nonparametric methods for theoretical neuroscience

3 / 2020 Neurocomputation and AI in Neuroscience, Cambridge Postdictive inference in perception

SKILLS

PUBLICATIONS

Referred journals and conference proceedings

- LKW, ..., Arthur Gretton, Mark Rowland Distributional Bellman Operator on Mean Embeddings. Under review, 2023
- Grégoire Delétang, ..., LKW, ..., Marcus, Hutter, Joel Veness. Language modeling is compression. Under review, 2023
- Tianyuan Teng*, LKW*, Hang Zhang. Bounded Rationality in Structured Density Estimation. NeurIPS, 2023
- Tim Genewein, ..., LKW, ..., Joel Veness. Memory-Based Meta-Learning on Non-Stationary Distributions. ICML 2023
- Grégoire Delétang, ..., LKW, ..., Shane Legg, Pedro A Ortega. Neural networks and the Chomsky hierarchy. ICML, 2022
- LKW, Ben Moran. Score-based generative models learn manifold-like structures with constrained mixing. NeurIPS
 Workshop on score-based models, 2022
- Bin Dai, LKW, and David Wipf. On the Value of Infinite Gradients in Variational Autoencoder Models. NeurIPS, 2021
- Longyuan Li, Jian Yao, LKW, ..., David Wipf, Zheng Zhang. *GRIN: Generative Relation and Intention Network for Multiagent Trajectory Prediction*, NeurIPS, 2021
- LKW, Heishiro Kanagawa. Blindness of score-based methods to isolated components and mixing proportions. NeurIPS
 Workshop Your model is wrong: Robustness and misspecification in probabilistic modeling, 2021
- Tianlin Xu*, LKW*, Michael Munn, Beatrice Acciaio. COT-GAN: Generating sequential data via causal optimal transport. NeurIPS, 2020
- LKW, Theodore Moskovitz, Heishiro Kanagawa, Maneesh Sahani. Amortised learning by wake-sleep. ICML, 2020
- LKW, Maneesh Sahani. A Plausible model for online recognition and postdiction in dynamic environment. NeurIPS,
 2019
- LKW*, Dougal Sutherland*, Heiko Strathmann, and Arthur Gretton. Learning deep kernels for exponential family densities. ICML, 2019
- LKW and Aaron Seitz. Deep neural network for modelling visual perceptual learning. Journal of Neuroscience, 2018
- Chunfang Liu, Wenliang Li, Funchun Sun, Jianwei Zhang. Grasp planning by human experience on objects with complex geometry. IROS, 2015

Referred conference abstracts

- Tianyuan Teng*, LKW*, Hang Zhang. Economically expanding internal models in human density estimation. CCN, 2022
- LKW. A distributional Bayesian learning theory for visual perceptual learning. COSYNE, 2022
- LKW, Eszter Vértes, Maneesh Sahani. Accurate and adaptive recognition in a dynamic environment. COSYNE, 2019
- LKW, Maneesh Sahani. Neural network represents uncertainty by nonlinear moments. COSYNE, 2018